Christopher Hedlund

Hillsboro, OH | christopher.m.hedlund@gmail.com | 443.417.3490

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-hedlund-a6013b8a | GitHub: https://github.com/swedishkinda

Portfolio: https://swedishkinda.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary Web Developer with a passion for front-end development. Experience building websites with JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and jQuery from start to finish and seeing strong outcomes when deploying. Adapts well to diverse working environments and collaborating with teams. Brings experience obtained through meticulous design. Prepared to excel in solving complex problems.

SKILLS

Web Development: JavaScript ES5/ES6, jQuery, API's, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and Flexbox

Databases: Mongo, SQL, FireBase

Miscellaneous: Microsoft Office, Git/Github, Adobe Suite

PROJECTS

ED SITE: https://github.com/swedishKinda/Educational Site https://swedishkinda.github.io/Educational Site

- An educational website with different kinds of interactives.
- **Technologies:** Bootstrap, Flexbox, JavaScript ES6, jQuery, and Slick.

My Chef: https://github.com/swedishKinda/My-Chef2 https://swedishkinda.github.io/My-Chef2/

- JavaScript application that essentially returns a list of drink or meal recipes based on a given ingredient.
- Technologies: AJAX calls to two separate API's, JQuery library for "Slick" carousel, and "modal" alerts

Liri Node App: https://github.com/swedishkinda/liri-node-app https://youtu.be/v3Cd6raLesY

- App where the user can search for a song on Spotify, a movie on IMDB, or for a concert on Bandsintown.
- Technologies: JavaScript ES6, Node.js, and NPMs FS, Inquirer, Spotify, Axios, Moment, and Dotenv.

EXPERIENCE

Apr. 2020 - Feb. 2024 **Accelerate Education**

Front-End Web Developer

- Develop websites to be used in online learning environments.
- Display in depth knowledge of jQuery, JavaScript ES5/ES6, HTML5, CSS3, and Adobe Suite.

DoorDash Mar. 2015 - Current

Associate/Driver

US Aquatics: Beltsville, MD Apr. 2011- Mar. 2015

Regional Manager (Philadelphia Area)

- Interacted with clients to ensure quality customer service. And worked with local governmental operations to see that all standards are met.
- Performed the ability to work independently without direct oversight, but in an overall team environment.

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania LPS Coding Bootcamp, Philadelphia, PA

Oct. 2019

Certificate Full-Stack Web Development

University of Maryland, Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD

Mechanical Engineering and Environmental Science

Dec. 2007